Guide to the Historic Photographs and Drawings Collection Photo.002
New York University Archives
- Series I: Oversized Photographs and Drawings
  - Tech II Building- NYU University Heights Campus (photograph), undated; 18x12 mounted color photograph on RC paper(?) Recto: photograph is peeling along the edges Verso: adhesive appears to have skinned layers of the mounting, writing in pencil, yellow stains from what appears to have been an adhesive in all four corners Condition: Good (Box Shared University Archives 145, Folder 7)
  - Tech II Building- NYU University Heights Campus (photograph), 1969; 22x17 mounted black and white photograph Photo size: 17x11.5 Mounting size: 22x17 Recto: multiple writings in black pen, blue pen, and pencil, pressure adhesive on left and right sides Verso: writing in pencil, writing in red pen, black and brown scratches, surface dirt Condition: Good (Box Shared University Archives 145, Folder 7)
  - Gould Memorial Library- NYU Heights Campus, undated; 20x24 mounted black and white photograph Recto: top left and right corners are severly bent, some abrasions along the edges Verso: peeling from what appears to be adhesive, writing in pencil, bends in corners Condition: Good (Flat-file 8, Drawer 1)
  - Aerial Photograph of University Heights Campus by Fairchild Aerial Survey, June 17, 1931; 21x16.5 mounted black and white photograph General: pieces missing from top right, bottom right and top left Recto: multiple tears along edges, Verso: sever skinning of mounting, discoloration from what appears to be adhesive, heavy surface dirt, three writings in pencil, Condition: Poor (Box Shared University Archives 127)
  - Aerial Photograph of NYU University Heights Campus by Fairchild Aerial Survey, December 21, 1920; 17x12 black and white photograph on fiber paper Recto: bend in bottom right corner Verso: stamp in purple ink, two writings in black pen, writing in pencil, discoloration along edges Condition: Good (Box Shared University Archives 145, Folder 8)
  - Aerial Photograph of NYU University Heights Campus, circa 1920-1921; 17x13.5 black and white photograph on fiber paper General: negative included in mylar with photograph Recto: slight scrathes and creases Verso: stamp in purple ink, two writing in black pen, three writings in pencil, writing in purple ink, discolorations from what appears to be adhesive Condition: Good (Box Shared University Archives 145, Folder 8)
  - Aerial Photograph of NYU University Heights Campus, 1937; 17x14 black and white photograph on fiber paper General: edges are cut unevenly Recto: white border with some black markings along the edges Verso: heavy surface dirt and discoloration from what appears to be adhesives, pressure adhesive, writing in pencil Condition: Good (Box Shared University Archives 145, Folder 8)
  - Photograph of Drawing of New York University and Reformed Dutch Church from circa 1850s, circa 1981; 12x8 photograph of black and white etching reproduction on RC paper General: planar distortion Recto: slight surface dirt Verso: slight surface dirt Condition: Good (Flat-file 5, Drawer 16)
  - New York University 150 Year Celebration Poster, 1981-1982; 11x17 color, printed poster General: 7 copies of this item Condition: Good (Flat-file 5, Drawer 16)
  - Regimental Parade, Washington Square 1851 by Otto Boetticher- Reproduction of original color painting, circa 1981; 16x12.5 reproduction of original color painting on poster paper General: 10 copies of this item Condition: Good (Flat-file 5, Drawer 16)
  - View of the University, in the City of New York- photograph of drawing from circa 1850s, 1967; 20x13 Photograph of black and white drawing on fiber paper General: Planar distortion Recto: surface dirt along edges Verso: stamp in purple, two types of writing in pencil Condition: Good (Flat-file 5, Drawer 16)
  - Photograph of NYU Library in Main Building Users and Card Catalog, November 23, 1955; 19.5x15.5 mounted black and white photograph Recto: corners curling and bending, scratches Verso: mounting is breaking off in corners, stamp in black ink, writing in pencil Condition: Good (Box Shared University Archives 127)
  - Photograph of NYU Library in Main Building Users and Circulation Desk, November 23, 1955; 19.5x15.5 mounted black and white photograph Recto: scratches, curling and tears at corners, Verso: surface dirt, stamp in black ink, writing in pencil, mounting broken and missing from bottom left corner Condition: Good (Box Shared University Archives 127)
  - Photograph of NYU Library in Main Building Users and Staff, November 23, 1955; 19.5x15.5 mounted black and white photograph Recto: scratches, curling and tears at corners, Verso: surface dirt, stamp in black ink, writing in pencil, mounting broken and missing from bottom left and right corner Condition: Good (Box Shared University Archives 127)
  - Reprint of Photograph of NYU Library in Main Building Users, Bookshelves and Tables, November 23, 1955; 19.5x15.5 mounted black and white photograph Recto: scratches, curling and tears at corners, Verso: surface dirt, stamp in black ink, writing in pencil, mounting broken and missing from bottom left corner, water stain (?) along bottom edge Condition: Good (Box Shared University Archives 127)
  - NYU Library in Main Building Users and Circulation Desk featuring Seymour James (photograph), circa 1955; 25.5x20 mounted black and white photograph Photo size: 19.5x15.5 Mounting size: 25.5x20 Recto: some breaks on the mounting, small scratches on photo, corners broken off of mounting Verso: writing in pencil, heavy surface dirt, black fingerprints (?) Condition: Good (Flat-file-folder 2 Right)
  - NYU Library in Main Building, Reserve Reading Room (photograph), circa 1955; 25.5x20 mounted black and white photograph Photo size: 19.5x15.5 Mounting size: 25.5x20 Recto: some surface dirt, corners missing from mounting Verso: heavy surface dirt, some dark stains, writing in pencil Condition: Good (Flat-file-folder 2 Right)
  - NYU Library in Main Building, interior, User at Card Catalog (photograph), circa 1955; 25.5x20 mounted black and white photograph Photo size: 19.5x15.5 Mounting size: 25.5x20 Recto: heavy surface dirt, color distortion on bottom right corner of photograph Verso: writing in pencil, heavy surface dirt, flaking of mounting at the corners Condition: Good (Flat-file-folder 2 Right)
  - Photograph of Corner of Waverly Place and Greene, circa 1980s; 11x14 black and white photograph on RC paper General: planar distortion/curling at edges Verso: black stamp Condition: Good (Flat-file 8, Drawer 2)
  - Photograph of Corner of Broadway and Washington Place, circa 1980s; 11x14 black and white photograph on RC paper General: planar distortion/curling at edges Verso: black stamp Condition: Good (Flat-file 8, Drawer 2)
  - Photograph of Corner of Washington Square Park East and West 4th Street (2 copies), undated; 20x16 black and white photograph on fiber paper General: Rippling/curling along edges Recto: discoloration/yellowing, surface dirt Verso: surface dirt, black mark in middle Condition: Good (Box Shared University Archives 127)
  - Photograph of two NYU students studying, circa early 1980s; 14x11 black and white photograph on fiber paper Recto: curling/planar distortion Verso: surface dirt/brownish stains, writing in pencil Condition: Good (Flat-file 8, Drawer 2)
  - Bobst Library, exterior rendering/drawing (photograph of drawing by Tesla), 1965 (Box Shared University Archives 045, Folder 5)
  - Yonkers Property Map- Photostat Negative, undated; 13x8.5 photostat negative General: corners curling, discoloration Condition: Good (Box Shared University Archives 129)
  - Certificate of Incorporation for New York University Law Alumni Association, Inc., October 15, 1940; 21x17 mounted printed certificate on fiber paper Mounting Frame Size: 21x17 Certificate Size: 17.5x14.5 Recto: mounting has fallen off of the recto, heavy surface dirt, tear in right top corner, black stains (soot?) deposit from adhesive, blue seal Verso: planar distortion, discoloration, staining from adhesive Condition: Fair (Flat-file 8, Drawer 4)
  - The Bicentennial/Institutional Related Program of the Year Certificate for New York University, July 4, 1976; 12.5x20 black print on fiber paper Recto: black printing, writing in black ink Condition: good (Box Shared University Archives 128)
  - New York University B.A. Diploma for George J. Meltzer from School of Architecture and Allied Arts and Washington Square College- facsimile, June 1947; 14x11 black and white facsimile of diploma Condition: Good (Box Shared University Archives 129)
  - Ferdinand Foch Receiving Doctor of Laws Degree from NYU Chancellor E.E. Brown: photograph, November 18, 1921; 10.5x12 mounted, painted (in color) black and white photograph Recto: small scratches Verso: two types of writing in pencil Condition: Good (Box Shared University Archives 128)
  - NYU Chancellor Brown and George Alexander: photograph, circa 1920s; 10x13 black and white photograph with white border on fiber paper Recto: discoloration/yellowing, small scratches, embossed imprint at bottom right corner Verso: tear on left side, writing in pencil, stamp in blue ink, heavy surface dirt General: Good (Box Shared University Archives 128)
  - General Armando Diaz and NYU Chancellor Brown: photograph, circa 1920s; 12.25x9.75 black and white (sepia tone) photograph Recto: black pen writing in bottom right corner, slight scratches Verso: heavy adhesive deposits where backing appears to have peeled off, writing in pencil Condition: Good (Box Shared University Archives 128)
  - Portrait of Chancellor E. E. Brown: photograph, 1910; 11x14 black and white photograph on fiber paper Recto: tattering along edges, bottom right corner missing, top right corner breaking off Verso: heavy surface dirt, discoloration/yellowing, writing in pencil, writing in black pen Condition: Good (Box Shared University Archives 128)
  - Unveiling of bust of George David Stewart, with Stewart, Mrs. Eddy Ellsworth Brown(?), George F. Baker, John H Tuildy(?), NYU Chancellor E.E. Brown, Unknown person, Dr. George Alexander, Dr. S.A. Brown, 1928; 19x12 black and white photograph Recto: breaks and tears along edges, bottom right corner missing Verso: writing in pencil, writing in black pen, heavy surface dirt, discoloration/yellowing, pressure adhesive along edges, some breaks and tears Condition: Poor (Box Shared University Archives 128)
  - Photograph of NYU Chancellor Brown, Onorio Ruotolo, Fiorello La Guardia, September 12, 1934; 14x11 mounted black and white photograph on fiber paper Mounting Size:; 14x11 Photo size: 9.5x6.5 General: negative included with photograph Recto: surface dirt on mounting, writing in black pen Verso: 3 writings in pencil Condition: Good (Box Shared University Archives 128)
  - Chancellor E.E. Brown: photograph portraits (2 copies), undated; 10x13.5 mounted black and white photograph on fiber paper Mounting Size: 10x13.5 Photo size: 7x9 Recto: break at top right corner, missing piece of bottom right corner Verso: surface dirt, discoloration/deposits from what appears to be adhesive, writing in pencil Condition: Good (Box Shared University Archives 128)
  - NYU Chancellor E.E. Brown: photograph portrait by Bachrach, undated; 12x17 mounted black and white photograph on fiber paper Mounting Size: 12x17 Photo size: 9x12 General: 2 copies of this item exist Recto: marks in pencil Verso: heavy surface dirt, small tears along edges Condition: Good (Box Shared University Archives 128)
  - NYU Chancellor E.E. Brown Reading At Desk: photograph, undated; 13x10 mounted black and white photograph on fiber paper Photo size: 10.5x8.5 Mounting Size: 13x10 Recto: yellowing/discoloration Verso: yellowing/discoloration, some surface dirt Condition: Good (Box Shared University Archives 128)
  - NYU Chancellor E.E. Brown and Mrs. Fanny Eddy Ellsworth Brown: portrait, undated; 13.5x10.5 mounted black and white photograph Photo size: 9x7.5 Mounting size: 13.5x10.5 Recto: signature in pencil at bottom right corner, crease at top right corner Verso: surface dirt, deposit possibly from adhesive, two writings in pencil, stamp in black ink Condition: Good (Box Shared University Archives 128)
  - NYU Chancellor E.E. Brown: portrait taken by Koike Studio, undated; 10x13.5 mounted black and white photograph Photo size: 7x9 Mounting size: 10x13.5 Recto: some surface dirt, printing in black ink Verso: writing in pencil, black and white printed label adhered to bottom left corner, some yellowing Condition: Good (Box Shared University Archives 128)
  - NYU Chancellor E.E. Brown in Graduation Gown, standing next to torch: photograph, undated; 10.5x13.5 black and white photograph Photo size: 7x9 Mounting size: 10.5x13.5 Recto: bottom right corner is missing, surface dirt, embossed printing from Campbell Studios Verso: heavy surface dirt, two writings in pencil, printed black and white label from studio Condition: Good (Box Shared University Archives 128)
  - NYU Chancellor E.E. Brown: photograph of painting portrait, dressed in robes, seated. Inscribed message from George R. Boynton, undated; 13x19 mounted black and white photograph on fiber paper Photo size:10x13 Mounting size:13x19 Recto: tears along edges, writing in pencil, black mark on bottom left corner, bend at top right corner Verso: two writings in pencil, yellowing/discoloration Condition: Good (Box Shared University Archives 128)
  - NYU Professor Gaston Wiet, n.d.; 10x12 black and white photograph on fiber paper Verso: writing in pencil Condition: Good (Flat-file 8, Drawer 7)
  - John Strobel: portrait photograph, undated; 11x14 black and white photograph on fiber paper curling and rippling Verso: writing in pencil Condition: good (Box Shared University Archives 130)
  - General A. (Armando?) Diaz in uniform: inscribed portrait, November 5, 1921; 8x13.5 mounted black and white photograph Photo size: 7x11.5 Mounting size: 8x13.5 Recto: writing in black pen, discoloration on mounting Verso: surface dirt Condition: Good (Box Shared University Archives 130)
  - Herbert R. Silverman, August 31, 1978; 11x14 black and white photograph with white border General: negative of this image included Verso: writing in pencil Condition: good (Box Shared University Archives 130)
  - Severo Ochoa, undated; 13.5x10.5 black and white photograph on fiber paper Verso: writing in blue pen and pencil Condition: Good (Box Shared University Archives 130)
  - Joseph French Johnson: photograph of printed etching portrait, undated; 15.5x20 mounted etching Image Size: 10x14.5 Mounting Size: 15.5x20 Recto: yellowing/discoloration on mounting, scratches on image, heavy surface dirt Verso: writing in pencil, writing in black pen, chipping of mounting Condition: Good (Box Shared University Archives 128)
  - Dean William Baer, n.d.; 15x19 mounted black and white photograph on fiber paper Recto: scratches, skinning along edges Verso: three writings in pencil, surface dirt, discoloration, scratches Condition: Good (Flat-file 8, Drawer 7)
  - Henry Martin Baird: photograph portrait, circa 1859-1902; 12x15 black and white photograph Photo size: 11x14 Mounting size: 12x15 General: planar distortion Recto: sever discoloration/yellowing, breaks along edges Verso: serve discoloration/yellowing, multiple writings in pencil, writing in black pen, chipping of mounting Condition: Fair (Box Shared University Archives 128)
  - Isaac Nordheimer: photograph of portrait (NYU professor, 1839-1842), 1920; 10x13.5 mounted black and white photograph Recto: bottom right corner is broken, flaking along edges Verso: writing in black pen Condition: Good (Box Shared University Archives 130)
  - Warren Weaver (Flat-file 8, Drawer 7)
  - John C. Sawhill - Federal Energy Administration press events and meetings photographs, 1974 (Box Shared University Archives 130)
  - Unknown boys choir in church (donated by Louis Snyder, class of 1897): photograph, undated (Box Shared University Archives 130)
  - James Stokes in office/classroom with two others, undated (Box Shared University Archives 130)
  - Frank J. Tasco portrait, undated (Box Shared University Archives 130)
  - Ernest Gottlieb Sihler: photograph of painted portrait, 1913; 10.5x14 mounted, painted photograph in color General: planar distortion Recto: signature in red pencil, flaking along edges Verso: yellowing/discoloration, writing in red pencil, writing in pencil, writing in blue pencil Condition: good (Box Shared University Archives 130)
  - NYU Chancellor Harry Chase: portrait, November 1937; 10x14 black and white photograph with white border on fiber paper Recto: tears, breaks and creases along edges, white printing from negative Verso: writing in pencil, surface dirt, discoloration along edges. Condition: Fair (Box Shared University Archives 130)
  - Leslie V. Carpenter, Professor of Engineering NYU, circa 1930-1940(?); 23x19 mounted black and white photograph on fiber paper Photo size: 14x17 Mounting size: 23x19 Recto: dirt and black marks on mounting, mounting is crumbling along edges Verso: two writings in pencil, discoloration/yellowing from what appears to be adhesive Condition: Good (Box Shared University Archives 128)
  - NYU Bobst Library Card Files Color Printed Drawing by Tesla, 1966; 30x20 mounted color print of drawing Mounting size: 30x20 Image size: 28.5x18 General: planar distortion Recto: tears in drawing Verso: writing in blue pen, pressure adhesive, discoloration Condition: Good (Drawer 11)
  - NYU Bobst Library Interior Color Printed Drawing by Tesla, 1966; 22.25x12 color print of drawing General: appears to be laminated in acidic material, planar distorion Recto: scratches, bends in corner Verso: writing in pencil, sever discoloration/yellowing Condition: Good (Drawer 11)
  - Lower Levels of NYU Bobst Library Color Printed Drawing by Tesla, 1966; 33x23.5 color print of drawing Image Size: 29x19 Mounting Size: 33x23.5 Recto: slight surface dirt on mounting Verso: writing in blue pen, deposits and discoloration from pressure adhesive Condition: good (Drawer 11)
  - Main Floor NYU Bobst Library Color Printed Drawing, 1966; 33.5x22.5 color printing of drawing Photo size: 30x20 Mounting size: 33.5x22.5 Recto: some surface dirt, staining from adhesive, scratches on image Verso: heavy surface dirt, writing in blue pen, writing in black pen, deposits/discoloration from adhesive Condition: Good (Drawer 11)
  - NYU Bobst Library Atrium, 1966; 33x22.5 mounted color print of drawing Photo size: 29x21.5 Mounting size: 33x22.5 Recto: tearing at edges, dark marks, surface dirt Verso: writing in blue pen, pressure adhesive along edges Condition: Good (Drawer 11)
  - NYU Varsity Baseball Team (photographic negative), 1899; 8x10 negative of black and white photograph. Stored in glassine paper. Condition: Good (Box Shared University Archives 131)
  - Negative of Photograph for NYU Fans Fighting on a field, n.d.; 8x10 negative of black and white photograph. Stored in glassine paper. Condition: Good (Box Shared University Archives 131)
  - Negative of Photograph for 1919-1920 NYU National Champion Basketball Team, 8x10 negative of black and white photograph. Stored in glassine paper. Condition: Good (Flat-file 8, Drawer 9)
  - Negative of Photograph for NYU Basketball Team 1947-1948, 8x10 negative of black and white photograph. Stored in glassine paper. Condition: Good (Box Shared University Archives 131)
  - Negative of Photograph for NYU Basketball Team 1957-1958, 8x10 negative of black and white photograph. Stored in glassine paper. Condition: Good (Box Shared University Archives 131)
  - Negative of Photograph for NYU Football Team, circa 1910; 8x10 negative of black and white photograph. Stored in glassine paper. Condition: Good (Box Shared University Archives 131)
  - Negative of Photograph for NYU Football Team, circa 1904; 8x10 negative of black and white photograph. Stored in glassine paper. Condition: Good (Box Shared University Archives 131)
  - Negative of Photograph for NYU Football Team, 1922; 8x10 negative of black and white photograph. Stored in glassine paper. Condition: Good (Box Shared University Archives 131)
  - School of Education at Camp Sebago. Joseph Mandel, Faculty, Shooting Bow and Arrow, undated; 10.5x14 black and white photograph on fiber paper Recto: some curling along edges, small tear along top edge,m bends on corners Verso: heavy surface dirt, writing in pencil Condition: Good (Box 28)
  - School of Education at Camp Sebago: group photograph, undated; 17x14 mounted black and white photograph Photo size: 14x11.5 Mounting size: 17x14 Recto: severe discoloration, water stain(?) along mounting and part of photograph, white writing from negative, yellowing along edges of mounting, bottom left corner of photo and mounting is missing Verso: heavy surface dirt and discoloration, planar distorition, water stains (?), three writings in pencil, pieces of mounting missing Condition: Fair (Box 28)
  - School of Education at Camp Sebago, building fires, undated; mounted black and white photograph Mounting and photo are the same size General: pieces missing from corner and edges Recto: tears in photographs and mountings along edges, some surface dirt Verso: heavy surface dirt, writing in pencil, writing in blue pencil Condition: Fair (Box 28)
  - Basketball Game at Madison Square Garden: Columbia University vs. NYU (original photograph, enlarged reprint, and negative), December 31, 1931; 20x11.5 black and white photograph on fiber paper General: pieces of edge and corners missing Recto: white writing from negative Verso: stamps in brown ink, two writings in pencil, heavy surface dirt, dark brown marks (possibly fingerprints). Condition: Fair (Box 24)
  - Basketball Game: NYU vs. Notre Dame at Madison Square Garden, December 29, 1934; 20x11 black and white photograph on fiber paper General: multiple breaks, pieces missing from top left and right corners. Recto: writing in white writing from negative Verso:heavy surface dirt, faded stamps at top and bottom Condition: Poor (Box 24)
  - Negative of Photograph for 1934 Basketball Game at Madison Square Garden- Notre Dame vs. NYU, December 29, 1934; 8x10 negative of black and white photograph. Stored in glassine paper. Condition: Good (Box 24)
  - Track Team group, photograph and negative, 1902; 13.5x10 mounted black and white photograph on fiber paper Recto: slight discoloration/fading Verso: heavy surface dirt, deposits from adhesive, writing in pencil Condition: Good (Box Shared University Archives 131)
  - NYU Track Team, circa 1904; 20x16 mounted black and white photograph. General: secondary mounting with archivally sound board, sealed in mylar Photo Size: 13.5x10 Mounting Size: 20x16 Recto: writing in pen on original mounting, crumbling corners on mounting, cracks and tears in mounting, stamp on mounting Verso: verso not visible behind archival, secondary mounting Condition: Good (Box 28)
  - NYU Track Team group photograph, 1904; 13.5x9.5 mounted black and white photograph Recto: black marks/scratches, flaking along edges, bottom left corner missing Verso: heavy surface dirt and discoloration, skinning Condition: Fair (Box Shared University Archives 131)
  - NYU Track Team, undated; 13.5x10.5 black and white photograph on fiber paper Recto: tiny tears along edges Verso: heavy surface dirt, dark brown marks (possibly finger prints) Condition: Good (Box Shared University Archives 131)
  - Track Team- Middle Atlantic States Champions group photograph, 1927; 13.5x11 black and white photograph on fiber papers General: extremely brittle, multiple breaks, pieces missing from three corners Recto: black writing from negative Verso: heavy discoloration/surface dirt, brown marks (possibly from fingerprints), writing in pencil Condition: Poor (Box Shared University Archives 131)